ILLIA DANKO

Software Engineer



illia.danko.me

Przemysl, PL

illia-danko



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Overall, eleven years of working experience in the field. Have participated in various technologies and programming languages, including Elixir, Javascript, Typescript, Golang, C, C++, Java, Clojure, and Python. Started as a system engineer and was moving to the Web, and Golang, in particular. I'm strongly focused on business' needs, and as a free software user, sometimes consider contributing further back to Open Source.

TECH STACK

General P	Purpose	Langu	lages
-----------	---------	-------	-------

Elixir Javascript Typescript Golang C Clojure Python C++ Java

Domain Specific Languages, frameworks and databases

Phoenix Html Sass & C	ss & Tailwindcss	React	Bash	Makefile	CMake	Javascript	Postgresql
MongoDB Elasticsearch	ArangoDB El	Lisp Lua	a LATEX	Protobu	Graph	ql	

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Aller Media Norway

Nov 2022 - Ongoing

- Ukraine, UA
- Design, develop and maintain core pipeline high throughput services.
- Develop UI Web tools using upstream technologies.
- Implement internal helper tools.
- Troubleshooting high performant components.

Stack

Golang design, prototype, implement and maintain services using google pubsub, redis, rest api and graphql, elastic-search, postgresql, docker and kubernetes. Write command line company centric tools.

Typescript / Javascript / React / Next.js implement and maintain UI admin panel using both: client and service side rending.

Phoenix Elixir / Ecto / Tailwindcss | design and implement internal tools and services.

Bash | ci/cd scripting.

Software Engineer

Aigent

Dec 2019 - Oct 2022

Amsterdam, NL

- Design, develop and maintain core pipeline services.
- Implement internal tools.
- Troubleshooting high performant components.
- Refine existing parts.
- Collaborate with clients.

Stack

Golang design, prototype, implement and maintain real time low latency microservies using kafka, memcached, rest api, rpcs, protobuf/msgpack, postgresql, arangodb, kubernetes. Write command line tools. Embed C libraries (cgo).

C write ffi libraries for other languages.

Javascript implement ecma5/6 compatible web applications, support react applications. Design, prototype and implement microservices using rest api, protobuf, mqtt, postgresql, kubernetes.

Clojure | implement microservices for features using rest api, elasticsearch, mqtt. Implement internal tools.

Python, Bash | ci/cd scripting.

Software Engineer

Omnisend

Feb 2018 - Dec 2019

Lviv, UA

- Design, develop and maintain high performing services.
- Cover with acceptance and e2e tests.

Stack

Golang design, implement and support features microsevices using rest api, grpc, nats, nsq, mongodb, kubernetes. Integrate 3d party platforms. Write command line tools.

Javascript Design, prototype and implement microservices using rest api, nsq, nats, mongodb.

Python, Bash ci/cd scripting.

Test Engineer

Here

i Jun 2017 - Feb 2018

Lviv, UA

- Design and develop integration testing framework.
- Implement and maintain integration tests for car navigation systems.

Stack

Python add features, maintain a testing framework using jenkins, sqlite3, casandra, hadoop map-reduce, aws s3, ec2, route algorithms (djaextra). ci/cd scripting.

Bash ci/cd scripting.

Middle Software Engineer

Cisco

■ Nov 2015 – Jun 2017

Lviv, UA

- Develop and maintain gateway systems for embedded devices.
- Develop and maintain primitive components and drivers, such as, voip, iptv, vpn.
- Write technical documentation.
- Participate in dmz room setup.
- Maintain and extend dmz testing framework.

Stack

C write and maintain modules for embedded equipment, including character and network devices using pki, httpd, tcp, udp, ppp, cgi, soap, tr-69, tr-98, tr-181, ieee 802.11, ethernet, ipv4, ipv6, dhcp.

Python add features to dmz testing framework using git hooks, jenkins, cisco hardware.

Software Engineer

Inside Secure

i Jul 2013 - Nov 2015

- Lviv. UA
- Develop and maintain a stereotyped simulator for credit card vendors.
- Write and maintain integration tests.

Stack

C++ implement and support visualization desktop gui tools (qt library), maintain nfs smartcards testing framework.

Java add features to mastercard nfs smardcards testing framework, maintain tools.

Python, Bash | ci/cd scripting.

SIDE PROJECTS

slivce.net - Wordle Game in Ukrainian. The main aim is to reduce the russian language's influence and to get people into Ukrainian vocabulary by having fun.

LANGUAGES

English Ukrainian

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Economics

Volodymyr Dahl East Ukrainian National University

Sep 2010 - Jun 2013